Guide to the Calvin Bryce Hoover Papers, 1922-1970
Duke University. University Archives
- General Correspondence
  - Research Council (Duke University), 1958-1967 (Box 20)
  - Reynolds Student Investment Fund, 1952-1957 (Box 20)
  - Richmond Trip, 1958 (Box 20)
  - Robert, Joseph C., 1944-1968 (Box 21)
  - Robinson, Allyn P., 1945-1965 (Box 21)
  - Robinson, E.A.G., 1949-1955 (Box 21)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1956, 1959 (Box 21)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1941-1958 (Box 21)
  - Rogers, Robert S., 1962, 1964 (Box 21)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1932 (Box 21)
  - Ross, John B., 1961-1967 (Box 21)
  - Ross, William Dee, Jr., 1947-1965 (Box 21)
  - Ruggles, Richard, 1954 (Box 21)
  - Russian Affairs (Professorship at Duke), 1961-1963 (Box 21)
  - Rutman, Gilbert L., 1962-1968 (Box 21)
  - S (miscellaneous), 1929-1949 (Box 21)
  - S (miscellaneous), 1950-1967 (Box 21)
  - Sabbatical Leave, 1962-1965 (Box 21)
  - Salary (Box 21)
  - Saylor, Ralph, 1964-1968 (Box 22)
  - Schaller, Howard G., 1956-1963 (Box 22)
  - Schrack, Joseph Earl, 1966 (Box 22)
  - Schrack, Roald, 1963 (Box 22)
  - Schweitzer, Arthur, 1946-1964 (Box 22)
  - Scott, John, 1958-1967 (Box 22)
  - Scott, Kerr, 1949-1957 (Box 22)
  - Scoville, Warren C., 1952 (Box 22)
  - Semans, James and Mary, 1956-1963 (Box 22)
  - Shepardson, Whitney, 1947-1963 (Box 22)
  - Shugerman, Abe Louis, 1947-1950 (Box 22)
  - Silk, Leonard Solomon, 1953-1966 (Box 22)
  - Simons, Rodger L., 1946-1959 (Box 22)
  - Singletary, W.E., 1949-1950 (Box 22)
  - Sontag, Raymond J., 1943-1968 (Box 22)
  - South Carolina Foundation of Independent Colleges, Inc., 1963-1964 (Box 22)
  - South Carolina University, 1963-1964 (Box 22)
  - Southern Bell Telephone Co., 1965-1966 (Box 22)
  - Southern Economic Journal, 1950-1958, 1960 (Box 22)
  - Spiro, Benjamin Paul, 1946-1954 (Box 22)
  - Springer, John Young, 1936-1947 (Box 23)
  - Standard Oil Co., 1949-1959 (Box 23)
  - Stewen, Martin K., 1958-1965 (Box 23)
  - Stigler, George, 1963 (Box 23)
  - Student Letters, 1960 (Box 23)
  - Swanson, Ernst, 1960, 1966 (Box 23)
  - T (miscellaneous), 1931-1967 (Box 23)
  - Takeuchi, Kenji, 1961-1968 (Box 23)
  - Tapp, Jesse, 1960 (Box 23)
  - Taylor, Horace, 1947-1952 (Box 23)
  - Texas Manufacturing Association, 1966 (Box 23)
  - Thames, H. Stanley, 1956 (Box 23)
  - Thomas, Brinley, 1956 (Box 23)
  - Thomas, Woodlief, 1954-1956 (Box 23)
  - Thompson, Paul W., 1961-1967 (Box 23)
  - Tikander, Wilho, 1950-1965 (Box 23)
  - Townsend, Roswell G., 1950 (Box 23)
  - Troxell, John P., 1945-1967 (Box 23)
  - Truman, Harry, 1948-1963 (Box 23)
  - Tugwell, Rexford G., 1933-1953 (Box 23)
  - Turner, Carl B., 1961-1967 (Box 23)
  - T.W.A. Marketair Service, 1965 (Box 24)
  - U (miscellaneous), 1925-1966 (Box 24)
  - Umstead, William B., 1947-1948 (Box 24)
  - United Nations Association of the USA, 1965 (includes Lyndon B. Johnson letter) (Box 24)
  - United States Information Agency, 1967 (Box 24)
  - University Memoranda, 1955, 1962 (Box 24)
  - University of North Carolina at Greensboro, 1966 (Box 24)
  - V (miscellaneous), 1931-1966 (Box 24)
  - Vandenberg, Arthur H., 1945-1950 (Box 24)
  - Van Voorhis, Robert H., 1944-1949 (Box 24)
  - Veterans (33rd Div. War Veterans Association), 1931-1967 (Box 24)
  - Viner, Jacob, 1950-1952 (Box 24)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review, 1945-1966 (Box 24)
  - Von Beckerath, Herbert, 1942-1958 (Box 24)
  - Voorhees, Tracy S., 1949-1957 (Box 24)
  - W (miscellaneous), 1930-1949 (Box 24)
  - W (miscellaneous), 1950-1959 (Box 24)
  - W (miscellaneous), 1960-1967 (Box 25)
  - Walter, James E., 1950-1956 (Box 25)
  - Wannamaker, W.H., 1941-1955 (Box 25)
  - Washington Post, 1949-1961 (Box 25)
  - Washington State University, 1963 (Box 25)
  - Watauga Club (Box 25)
  - Watkins, Ralph J., 1954, 1962 (Box 25)
  - Weekends at Duke, 1962 (Box 25)
  - Welfling, Weldon, 1941-1960 (Box 25)
  - Wells, O.V., 1947-1951 (Box 25)
  - Wesson, William Hinton, Jr., 1948-1961 (Box 25)
  - White House Conference, 1947, 1949 (Box 25)
  - White, William C., 1930-1931 (Box 25)
  - White, William S., 1963-1965 (Box 25)
  - Whitford, W.E., 1947-1962 (Box 25)
  - Whittlesey, C.R., 1952 (Box 25)
  - Wicker, E.R., 1952-1954, 1967 (Box 25)
  - Wiggins, J. Russell, 1936-1968 (Box 26)
  - Wilder, Francis S., 1946-1947 (Box 26)
  - Wiley, John & Sons, Inc., 1950-1955 (Box 26)
  - Williams, Bill J., 1942-1966 (Box 26)
  - Williams, M.J., 1948-1951 (Box 26)
  - Williamson, Hugh, 1931-1956 (Box 26)
  - Wilson, John D., 1946-1956 (Box 26)
  - Wilson, Robert R., 1944-1963 (Box 26)
  - Winfrey, John C., 1964-1966 (Box 26)
  - Winton, David J., 1948-1959 (Box 26)
  - Wisconsin, University of., 1956-1959 (Box 26)
  - Wolfard, Rodney B., 1946-1947 (Box 26)
  - Womble, B.S., 1961 (Box 26)
  - Wriston, Henry M., 1953, 1958 (Box 26)
  - Y (miscellaneous), 1947-1963 (Box 26)
  - Yale Review, 1945-1948 (Box 26)
  - Yntema, Theodore O., 1944-1954 (Box 26)
  - Yohe, William P., 1960-1966 (Box 26)
  - Young, James J., 1952-1961 (Box 26)
  - Young, Ralph A., 1959, 1965 (Box 26)
  - Young, Stanley, 1955-1956 (Box 26)
  - Youngson-Brown, A.J., 1956 (Box 26)
  - Z (miscellaneous), 1947-1951 (Box 26)
  - Unidentified Correspondents (Box 26)
  - Post-Retirement, 1968-1970 (Box 26)
  - Coil, E.J., 1948-1949 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - Comments on Preliminary Report to the Council of Economic Advisors, 1949 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - Committee of New England, 1951-1952 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - Committee of the South, 1954 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - Disposal of Southern War Plants, 1953 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - Fisk University (Inaugural Ceremonies), 1947-1948 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - French, Dr. Robert W., 1951-1952 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - Impact of Federal Policy on Economy of the South, 1949 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - Merrill Center for Economics, 1955 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - Nourse, Edwin G., 1949 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - National Planning Association, 1952-1956 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - O (miscellaneous), 1946, 1949, 1951 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - P (miscellaneous), 1948-1951 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - Palmer, Colonel E.W., 1950-1953 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - Parker, Virginia D., 1950 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - Sonne, H. Christian, 1954-1956 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - Stepp, James M., 1948 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - Stocking, George W., 1949-1953 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
  - United States Steel Corporation, 1948 (Box 27 (National Planning Association))
- Writings
  - List of Publications (2 folders) (Box 28)
  - A Criticism of 'Profits' (Box 28)
  - PhD Dissertation (Box 28)
  - The Paths of Economic Change: Contrasting Tendencies in the Modern World (Box 28)
  - Laissez Faire and Dictatorships (Box 28)
  - After Inflation (Box 28)
  - Capitalism and the Canon Law (Box 28)
  - Al Smith and the Gotterdammerung (Box 28)
  - Human Problems in Acreage Reduction in the South (Box 28)
  - The Economic Background of Southern Politics (Box 28)
  - Notes Dealing with Theory, 1926 (Box 28)
  - "Samarcand to Madrid," 1926 (Box 29)
  - Planning Production for Adequate Consumption, 1926 (Box 29)
  - The Market System as an Organizing Device for Economic Resources and the Changing Attitudes about Government Intervention in that System, 1926 (Box 29)
  - The Sea Loan in Genoa in the Twelfth Century, 1926 (Box 29)
  - The South is Still Solid, 1926 (Box 29)
  - Velocity of Bank Deposits an Important Factor in Growth of Brokers' Loans, 1928 (Box 29)
  - Economic Forces in the Evolution of Civil and Canon Law, 1929 (Box 29)
  - Brokers' Loans and Bank Deposits, 1929 (Box 29)
  - The Fate of the New Economic Policy of the Soviet Union, 1930 (Box 29)
  - Some Economic and Social Consequences of Russian Communism, 1930 (Box 29)
  - The Soviet Challenge to Capitalism, 1930 (Box 29)
  - Religion in Soviet Russia, 1931 (Box 29)
  - Socialism in Practice, 1931 (Box 29)
  - La Concurrence Sovietique Sur Le Marche International, 1931 (Box 29)
  - Sowjetkultur, 1931 (Box 29)
  - The Five Year Plan, [1931?] (Box 29)
  - Russian - The Unknown Quantity, 1932 (Box 29)
  - Abstract Russia and the World Depression, 1932 (Box 29)
  - Soviet Russia and the Prospect for World Peace, 1932 (Box 29)
  - Several chapters of typed manuscript of The Economic Life of Soviet Russia (Box 29)
  - Reviews of The Economic Life of Soviet Russia (Box 29)
  - Brokers' Loans and Bank Credit (Box 29)
  - Appendix to The Economic Life of Soviet Russia (Box 30)
  - The Economic Life of Soviet Russia (English, Chinese, French and Hungarian translations) (Box 30)
  - Germany Enters the Third Reich (English and French translations) (Box 30)
  - Reviews of Germany Enters the Third Reich (Box 30)
  - Germany Enters the Third Reich, manuscript, chapters 1-3 (Box 30)
  - Germany Enters the Third Reich, manuscript, chapters 4-6 (Box 31)
  - Germany Enters the Third Reic h, manuscript, chapters 7-8 (Box 31)
  - The Nazis and German Capitalism, 1933 (Box 31)
  - Human Problems in Acreage Reduction, 1934 (Box 31)
  - Dictators and Democracies, 1934 (Box 31)
  - Dictators Today: Benito Mussolini, Adolf Hitler, Joseph Stalin and Others, 1934 (Box 31)
  - The 'New Deal' in the United States, I. The Agricultural Adjustment Act: Principles, Practices and Problems, 1934 (Box 31)
  - Dictators Today, 1934 (Box 31)
  - The Paths of Economic Change: Contrasting Tendencies in the Modern World, 1935 (Box 31)
  - Radio Addresses, 1935 (Box 31)
  - Untitled Article, 1935 (Box 31)
  - Book Review on Economic Essays in Honor of Wesley Clair Mitchell, 1935 (Box 31)
  - The Status of the Consumer During the Life of the Agricultural Adjustment Act, 1936 (Box 31)
  - What are the Advantages and Disadvantages of Alternatives of Capitalism, 1936 (Box 31)
  - Possibilities of Agrarian Reorganization, 1936 (Box 31)
  - Dictators and Democracies, 1937 (Box 31)
  - Reviews of Dictators and Democracies, 1937 (Box 31)
  - From Czar to Stalin: Twenty Fateful Years, 1937 (Box 32)
  - Some Problems of Economic Planning by Government, 1938 (Box 32)
  - Agrarian Reorganization in the South, 1938 (Box 32)
  - Germany and Russia: Are They Alike?, 1938 (Box 32)
  - Dictatorship in the Modern World, 1939 (Box 32)
  - The Economics of Fascism, 1939 (Box 32)
  - Centennial Celebration, Duke University, April 21-23, 1939 (Box 32)
  - Germany's Power In the Present War, 1939 (Box 32)
  - Russia and Its Relation to the International Situation, 1939 (Box 32)
  - What Changes in National Policy does the South Need?, 1940 (Box 32)
  - American War Vote Demanded; Somme is Cited as our 'Frontier,' 1940 (Box 32)
  - Economic Planning and the Problem of Full Employment, 1940 (Box 32)
  - Articles on World War II Issues, 1940-1941 (Box 32)
  - Guns for the U.S. -- And Butter, Too, 1941 (Box 32)
  - Quick Action Urged to Curb War Price Boosts, 1941 (Box 32)
  - The Requirements of a War Economy, 1941 (Box 32)
  - The Economic Impact of Totalitarianism on the United States, 1941 (Box 32)
  - Post-War Economic Stumbling Blocks between U.S. and Britain, 1944 (Box 32)
  - American Foreign Trade and Investment, 1944 (Box 32)
  - Capitalism and Socialism, a New Soviet Appraisal, 1944 (Box 32)
  - Manufactures in our Foreign Trade, 1944 (Box 32)
  - Letters to: Morganthau Plan Discussed, 1944 (Box 33)
  - Rebuilding War Trade, 1945 (Box 33)
  - International Trade and Domestic Employment, 1945 (Box 33)
  - The Meaning of the Hour, 1945 (Box 33)
  - The British Loan, 1946 (Box 33)
  - The Future of the German Economy, 1946 (Box 33)
  - The Economic Issues of the Coming Election, 1946 (Box 33)
  - Soviet Economic Policies at Home and Abroad, 1947 (Box 33)
  - The Sources of Soviet Conduct, 1947 (Box 33)
  - Soviet Rule Blocks Atomic Pact, 1947 (Box 33)
  - Home Use for Export Surpluses, 1947 (Box 33)
  - How Much American Aid for Europe?, 1947 (Box 33)
  - European Recovery and American Aid, 1947 (Box 33)
  - Recent Economic Changes in the South, 1947 (Box 33)
  - Basic Elements in Soviet-American Relations, 1947 (Box 33)
  - Summary and Appraisal of Papers on the I.T.O. Charter, 1948 (Box 33)
  - Will the Marshall Plan Succeed?, 1948 (Box 33)
  - The European Recovery Program, 1948 (Box 33)
  - What Can Europe Do for Itself?, 1948 (Box 33)
  - Keynes and the Economic System, 1948 (Box 33)
  - Germany and European Economic Recovery, 1948 (Box 34)
  - Showdown with Weakness, 1948 (Box 34)
  - Money for Defense, 1948 (Box 34)
  - Some Aspects of the European Recovery Program, 1948 (Box 34)
  - International Economic Outlook: The Next Four Years, 1948 (Box 34)
  - Introduction of Mr. Alfred P. Sloan, 1948 (Box 34)
  - Meaning of the Spy Probe, 1948 (Box 34)
  - The Impact of Federal Policies on the Economy of the South, 1949 (Box 34)
  - Research Program of the Committee of the South, 1949 (Box 34)
  - Scrutinizing Aid Program, 1949 (Box 34)
  - Economic and Political Recovery in Europe, 1949 (Box 34)
  - Economic Policies for the South, 1949 (Box 34)
  - The Character and Significance of the General Commitments that Nations will make under the I.T.O. Charter, 1949 (Box 34)
  - Impact of Federal Policies on Regional Economic Development, 1949 (Box 34)
  - European Economic Recovery: The Record to Date and the Problems Remaining, 1949 (Box 34)
  - World Trade and the British Crisis, 1949 (Box 34)
  - Anglo-U.S. Understanding Chief Conference Aim, 1949 (Box 34)
  - Greetings from the Faculty, 1949 (Box 34)
  - Editorial, 1950 (Box 34)
  - Germany and the Future of Europe: The Economic Problem, 1950 (Box 34)
  - Book Review on My Three Years in Moscow, 1950 (Box 34)
  - Change in Economic Order, 1950 (Box 34)
  - Economic Resources and Policies of the South, 1951 (Box 34)
  - Germany, The Economic Problem, 1951 (Box 34)
  - Foreign Economic Aid and Communism, 1951 (Box 34)
  - Book Review on The Economics on Collective Action, 1951 (Box 34)
  - Communist Prisoners, 1952 (Box 34)
  - Economic Trends in Europe, The European Political Scene, Prospects for European Solvency, 1952 (Box 34)
  - The Soviet State Fails to Wither, 1952 (Box 34)
  - Institutional and Theoretical Implications of Economic Change, 1953 (Box 34)
  - Institutional and Theoretical Implications of Economic Change, 1954 (Box 34)
  - The Soviet Economic System, 1954 (Box 35)
  - Ending the Indo-China War, 1954 (Box 35)
  - Fundamental Issues Which Must be Faced in Agricultural Price Programs, 1954 (Box 35)
  - Introduction, for Selected Studies of Negro Employment in the South, 1954 (Box 35)
  - The European Exporters Point of View, 1955 (Box 35)
  - The Relevance of the Competitive, Laissez Faire Economic Model to Modern Capitalistic National Economies, 1955 (Box 35)
  - Ideology and Reality in the Soviet System: Economic Aspects, 1955 (Box 35)
  - The American Organizational Economy, 1955 (Box 35)
  - Scope and Objectives of Ten Sessions on Economic Growth, 1955 (Box 35)
  - Economic Growth I. Statement of the Problem of Keeping the United States Economy Moving Forward, but Steadily, Scope and Objects of Ten Sessions on Economic Growth, 1956 (Box 35)
  - Russian Trek for Fund Author, 1956 (Box 35)
  - Soviet Economic Growth, 1957 (Box 35)
  - Lecture I: The International Economic Picture, Lecture II: Russia, the X in the International Economic Equation, 1957 (Box 35)
  - Perils and Potentialities of a Policy of Coexistence with Soviet Russia, 1958 (Box 35)
  - Book Review on The Economics of Communist Eastern Europe, 1958 (Box 35)
  - Warning from Plutarch, 1959 (Box 35)
  - Survival of Liberty Rests on Evolution of Capitalism, 1959 (Box 35)
  - Factors Conducive to Bigness in Business, 1959 (Box 35)
  - Long Run Determinants of U.S. Economic Growth, 1959 (Box 35)
  - Can Capitalism Win the Intellectuals?, 1959 (Box 35)
  - Denationalization, 1959 (Box 35)
  - Conservation Acquiescence in Changed American Economy, 1959 (Box 35)
  - Is the United States a Backward Country in Current Economic Growth? Rates of Economic Growth, the United States, Soviet Russia, and Western Europe, 1959 (Box 35)
  - The Intellectual Capitalism, 1959 (Box 35)
  - The Economy, Liberty and the State, 1959 (English and German translations) (Box 36)
  - The Economy, Liberty and the State, 1959 (Spanish and Japanese translations) (Box 36)
  - Book Review on Conservatives in Power, A Study in Frustration, 1960 (Box 37)
  - Revolutions and Tyranny, 1960 (Box 37)
  - Book Review on Power without Property, 1960 (Box 37)
  - Economic and Social Change, Lecture - Worldwide Changes in Economic, Political and Social Institutions, Lecture - The Current Form of Capitalism in the United States, 1960 (Box 37)
  - The Economic Conflict, 1960 (Box 37)
  - Book Review on The Corporation in Modern Society, 1960 (Box 37)
  - Employment, Growth, and Price Levels: A Review Article, 1960 (Box 37)
  - Book Review on Khrushchev's Russia, 1960 (Box 37)
  - National Policy and Rates of Economic Growth: the United States, Soviet Russia, and Western Europe, 1960; Special Edition, 1961 (Box 37)
  - Book Review on Introduction to the Theory of Interest, 1961 (Box 37)
  - Book Review on The Soviet Industrialization Debate, 1961 (Box 37)
  - On the Inequality of the Rate of Profit and the Rate of Interest, 1961; Comment, 1962 (Box 37)
  - Foreward, for The Structure of the Australian Economy, 1962 (Box 37)
  - The American Organizational Economy, 1962 (Box 37)
  - The Role of Cost in the Minimum Pricing of Railroad Services, 1962 (Box 37)
  - The Challenge of Communism, 1962 (Box 37)
  - Economic Growth: Russia vs. the Capitalist Economies, 1962 (Box 37)
  - Foreshortening History, Economic Reform vs. Economic Growth in Underdeveloped Countries, 1963 (Box 37)
  - The Roles of the Natural and Developed Resources of the Nation States, 1963 (Box 37)
  - 'Rising Expectations' Must Be Postponed, 1963 (Box 37)
  - Capitalism, circa 1963 (Box 37)
  - Problems in Continuance of United States Economic Aid to Underdeveloped Countries, 1964 (Box 37)
  - The Roles of the Natural and Developed Resources of the Nation States, 1964 (Box 37)
  - The Privilege of a College Degree: Then and Now, 1964 (Box 37)
  - External Economic Aid to Underdeveloped Countries of the Commonwealth, 1964 (Box 37)
  - Comparative Economics and Politics, 1964 (Box 37)
  - The Soviet-Chinese Rivalry in Economic Aid to Underdeveloped Countries, 1964 (Box 37)
  - My Life at the University, 1965 (Box 38)
  - Memoirs of Capitalism, Communism, and Nazism, 1965 (Box 38)
  - Memoirs of Capitalism, Communism, and Nazism, Draft (Box 38)
  - The Inequality of the Rate of Profit and the Rate of Interest Revisited, 1965 (Box 38)
  - Introduction of President, and Presentation of Awards, American Economic Association, 1965 (Box 38)
  - A Love-Hate Relationship, 1966 (Box 38)
  - Our Foreign Policy from Pearl Harbor to Vietnam, 1966 (Box 38)
  - New Dimensions of a Continuing Problem: Workable Relations between Government and Corporate Industry, 1966 (Box 38)
  - Book Review on Challenge, 1966 (Box 38)
  - Economic and Political Consequences of Over-Extension in our Foreign Policy, 1966 (Box 38)
  - The Splintered Soviet-Chinese Bloc, 1967 (Box 38)
  - Competition in the United States, Its Developing Forms and Its Alternatives, 1967 (Box 38)
  - Capitalism, 1968 (Box 38)
  - Publication Agreements (Box 38)
  - A Decade of Commonwealth, 1966 (Box 38)
  - Economic Resources and Policies of the South Correspondence and Reviews, 1950-1951 (Box 38)
  - The Economy, Liberty and the State Correspondence, 1960-1967 (Box 39)
  - The Economy, Liberty and the State Reviews, 1959 (Box 39)
  - The Economy, Liberty and the State High School Version, 1962-1964 (Box 39)
  - Memoirs of Capitalism, Communism and Nazism, Correspondence, 1961-1967 (Box 39)
  - Letters and Comments from Recipients of Memoirs, 1965-1966 (Box 39)
  - Reviews of Memoirs, 1965-1967 (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous Materials re: Memoirs (Box 39)
  - Lists of People Who were Sent Copies and Advertisements of Memoirs (Box 39)
  - Unabridged Copy of Memoirs (approx. 15-20% of text herein was eliminated from final publication), pgs. 1-231 (Box 40)
  - Unabridged Copy of Memoirs, pgs. 232-end (Box 40)
  - Twentieth Century Fund, Correspondence (inc. material on Import Study), 1950-1953 (Box 40)
  - Distribution Theory, first draft, undated (Box 40)
  - Distribution Theory, second draft, undated (Box 40)
  - Conceptual and Measurement Problems in Distribution Theory, 1967 (Box 40)
  - Twentieth Century Fund, Correspondence, 1955-1968 (Box 40)
  - Twentieth Century Fund, Expenditures, 1950-1951 (Box 40)
  - Twentieth Century Fund, Press Conference, 1955 Nov. 30 (Box 40)
  - Economic Systems of the Commonwealth - Hoover's Chapter (Box 41)
  - Economic Systems of the Commonwealth - G. C. Allen's Chapter Economic System of the UK (Box 41)
  - Economic Systems of the Commonwealth - O. P. F. Horwood's Chapter Economic System of South Africa (Box 41)
  - Economic Systems of the Commonwealth - Nural Islam's Chapter Economic System of Pakista n (Box 41)
  - Economic Systems of the Commonwealth - Peter Karmel's Chapter Economic System of Australia (Box 41)
  - Economic Systems of the Commonwealth - W. Arthur Lewis' Chapter Economic System of the West Indian Federation (Box 41)
  - Economic Systems of the Commonwealth - O. W. Main's Chapter Economic System of Canad a (Box 41)
  - Economic Systems of the Commonwealth - Henry M. Oliver's Chapter Economic System of Ceylon (Box 41)
  - Economic Systems of the Commonwealth - Palamadai S. Lakanathan's Chapter Economic System of India (Box 41)
  - Economic Systems of the Commonwealth - T. H. Silcock's Chapter Economic System of Singapore and Malaya (Box 41)
  - Economic Systems of the Commonwealth - Colin Simkin's Chapter Economic System of New Zealand (Box 41)
  - Economic Systems of the Commonwealth - J. W. Williams' Chapter Economic System of Ghana (Box 41)
  - Economic Systems of the Commonwealth - Miscellaneous (Box 41)
  - Economic Systems of the Commonwealth - Sketches about the Authors (Box 41)
  - Unused Article Material and Drafts (Box 42)
  - Book Review on The Soviet Industrialization Debate, 1924-1928 (Box 42)
  - The Collapse of Marxism, Socialis m (Box 42)
  - Nationalist Socialist Germany (Box 42)
  - Bulk Trades with Russia (Box 42)
  - The Nature of the Drouth [Drought] (Box 42)
  - Philosophy of the New Deal (Box 42)
  - Price Production Control and Consumption (Box 42)
  - Purchasing Power in its Relationship to Bank Credit (Box 42)
  - Three Competing Systems: Capitalism, Fascism, Communism (Box 42)
  - The Civilization of the Soviets (Box 42)
  - Book Review on My Russian Neighbors (Box 42)
  - The Agricultural Adjustment Act: Principles, Practices, and Problems (Box 42)
  - Causes and Consequences of the Agricultural Adjustment Administration (Box 42)
  - Speech on Drought (Box 42)
  - Chicago Slim, as Calvin Van Pelt (Box 42)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 42)
  - Book Drafts, undated [book title(s) unknown] (See Box 75, legal size folder) (Box 42)
- Academic Material
  - Bell, Gordon, 1954-1957 (Box 42)
  - Black, Martin L., 1943-1957 (Box 42)
  - Cartter, Allan M., 1952-1957 (Box 42)
  - de Vyver, Frank T., 1939-1959 (Box 42)
  - Dewey, Donald J., 1949-1958 (Box 42)
  - Dickens, Robert, 1956-1957 (Box 42)
  - Gottheil, Fred M., 1956 (Box 42)
  - Ferguson, C. E., 1957-1961 (Box 42)
  - Hanes, P. Huber, 1960-1965 (Box 42)
  - Hanna, Frank T., 1950-1961 (Box 42)
  - Hanna's Tables (Box 42)
  - Hasenberg, Irene, 1956 (Box 43)
  - Hoover, C. B.,1953, 1955, 1957, undated (Box 43)
  - Humphrey, Don, 1946-1957 (Box 43)
  - Huntley, Patrick, 1957-1958 (Box 43)